CADEN COLLINS

610703 NE 44TH ST VANCOUVER, WA 98682

SUMMARY:

A passionate and motivated student of technology, as well as a fast learner. Currently studying / enrolled for the CCNA, Comptia Network/ Security/ A + certifications at New Horizons Computer Learning Center. I am also US Army veteran, who has leadership experience directly facing challenging situations, team leadership, problem-solving skills, strong time management, organizational skills, strong analytical thinking and planning skills, adaptability skills, and has strong resistance to stress.

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS:

Skills

- Analytic Skills
- Communication Skills
- Good Team Player
- Multitasking
- Problem Solving
- Technological Expertise
- Time Management
- Fluent in English (written and verbal)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

Remotely

10/2021 - Current

Operations/IT support - Portland,OR

- Configuring DHCP, DNS and other configs on pf Sense firewall and windows server 2019
- Set up and managed Resilio and LTO7 tape writing as a media manager on Magstar/Q40
- Troubleshooting driver issues on cards such as ATTO H1280 + H1280 GT
- Installing ATTO SAS or FC interfaces,
- Fiber install (fiber switch/cabling)
- Setting up and managing LAN pc's and MAC's with active directory
- Experienced in setting up RAIDS with TruNAS software
- Experienced in Proxmox setting up OS's

COMPASS SECURITY

06/2021 - 10/2021

Security Officer - Portland, OR

- Hands on experience in detaining / escorting subjects off store property
- Experienced and trained in self-defence on protecting and fending off subjects with lethal / non lethal tools.
- Well versed in building profiles for on subjects.

WWTS

(World Wide Tech Solutions), Portland, Oregon

ENGINEER

01/2021 - 04/2021

- Help solve technical problems in the field with computers.
- Complete work orders on part replacements for customer devices.
- Help solve any customer computer related issues including BIOS updates, flashing / imaging, hard drive replacement, motherboard replacements ets.

G4S, Portland, Oregon Customs Protection Officer

05/2019 - 01/2021

- Work in cooperation with Corporate Security department while providing a safe and secure environment. Both through the execution of departmental policies and proactively detecting and mitigating a threat.
- Responsible for providing accurate, timely reports, responding to daily activities, incident reports, and emergency actions.

- Able to execute life safety procedures and restraint to protect associates in various emergency situations using non-violent crisis intervention, defense, and restraint techniques.
- Detect, investigate, and deny access to unauthorized individuals + Respond to any
 emergency situation in a timely and professional manner + Observe departing
 personnel to protect against theft of company property and ensures that authorized
 removal of property is conducted within appropriate client requirements + Investigate
 and prepare reports on accidents, incidents, and suspicious activities; maintain written
 logs as required by the post + Provide assistance to customers, employees and visitors.

US ARMY 04/2017 – 11/2018

31 B (Military Police) onsite Dague, South Korea

- Plan, organize, and lead troops and activities in military operations. Manage enlisted personnel. Operate and command while on aircraft, ships, or armored vehicles. Provide medical, legal, engineering, and other services to military personnel.
- Conducted law enforcement on military installations and responded to medical and fire.
- Conducted FTX missions in South Korea with 188th CO
- Honorably Discharged, 19 months and 16 days duty

Hampton Lumber Internship

07/2019 - 10/2019

- Spent hours of lab time with the company with skills on troubleshooting, routing and switching.
- Time with configuring firewalls, static and dynamic routes, routing protocols, software patching and updating, virtualization and hardware and software fundamentals.

Freelance Network Engineer Student

02/2019 - present Experience 1.8+

- Planned, designed, and installed network Ensured redundance, scalability, and security on all networks in lab environment / real devices.
- Created and configured 100 + VPNs in lab time.
- Created 20+ secure networks, both local and wide-area.
- Performed troubleshooting an load-balancing on lab devices...
- Deployed dynamic routing protocols such as EIGRP, OSPF ect

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

- Hardware/Software/Network Fundamentals
- Operating Systems
- Virtualization
- Windows / Linux
- Firewall Configuration
- PowerShell
- Software Patching and Updating
- Configuring Windows Security

Labs

- CCNA
- CONFIGURATION
- LAN SWITCHING
- VLSM (variable-length subnet mask)
- Wireless Networking
- SDN, CBN

Computer Skills

- Microsoft Office
- PuTTY, WireShark
- ZenMap, NMap
- GNS3, IPerf, Packet Tracer
- Install and remove discrete components (e.g. Add/remove memory, Storage, PSU, CMOS battery, etc.)
- install and configure Windows and Linux Operating systems
- Configure BIOS/UEFI
- Perform basic OS and HW troubleshooting
- Documenting troubleshooting steps
- Installation of Software
- Practical understanding of Wired and Wireless networking

EDUCATION:

- New Horizons Computer Learning Center, Phoenix, AZ 05/2021 Present
- Computer and Network Technology, CIS 120 Computer Concepts
 Portland Community College, Portland, OR
 02/2019 05/2019
- Graduated with Distinction (Grade 1 A/excellent equivalent in computer science)
 Gresham High School, Gresham, OR
 09/2013 05/2017

CERTIFICATION:

CCNA (Cisco Certified Network Associate)
 Currently studying and working towards.

VOLUNTEERING:

Pitbulls For Life Rescue - Grants pass - United States Caretaker

03/2013 - 03/2016

Gave care to animals. Would feed, water, bathe, groom, and exercise animals. Then play
with animals and provide companionship to them. Then watch animals, record their
condition, and report any problems.

CONTACT:

Email: Ace@networkginen.com

Phone: 573-433-1152